[Music]
the following is a production of Frankie
Freitas and the internet Museum of
hologography
[Music]
hello everyone this is Frankie Freitas
and welcome to another week of holotalk
for the week of May 24
1999. welcome to the show this is a
special show in two respect number one
this is the last show of the Season uh
whole talk is off each year Memorial Day
has the summer off and then comes back
Labor Day with a brand new season of
shows but we have the reruns for you to
enjoy all summer long until we come back
the second special thing is the fact
that this is not only being broadcast
and audio but it's being broadcast in
video as well so if you have real player
which supports video just look on the
whole talk page to see the link that
says watch the show click on it and
you'll be able to see into the whole
talk Studios now the reason why I'm
doing this right now is what I'd like to
eventually do with this camera is to
take it out on the road to maybe
different holography events or if a
holographer happens to be in town or
someone's in the studio we can do a
whole talk show in both audio and audio
and video so you can have a choice of
either just listening to the show or
tuning in and seeing the show as well so
that's going to be something we're going
to be doing next year Well actually this
year but next season which starts up
Labor Day which is I believe September
13th this year I'd also like to mention
about the email list now if you're on
the email list which gets updates
usually on a weekly basis you'll know
that this week's email told you that the
email list was going to be deleted and
that's true I do that at the end of each
season I completely clear out the email
list what you need to do if you'd like
to stay on the list is either respond to
that email
or on the whole talk page you'll see the
button which you can click on that says
updates and this will put you back on
the list again and we have a lot of
things coming up this summer and even
though there won't be any brand new
Hollow talk shows although we may sneak
a special one in now and then there's a
lot of exciting things that are coming
up especially in the next few weeks
Sam Savage is working with a 35
milliwatt diode and getting the power
supply together for that and what we're
going to do in the next couple weeks is
you're going to have an opportunity to
come back onto the website and see how
you can build your own 35 milliwatt
laser diode to do Holograms with and
we're thinking the price is going to be
around 75 dollars in order for you to do
that everything that you need that will
take the place
of a standard 35 milliwatt laser helium
neon laser so that's very exciting we're
going to have that entire report up at
the site if you're not on the email list
anymore you will not get an email
telling you that this is up there so I
suggest that you respond to that email
get back on the email list if you wish
to get information on that
a lot of exciting stuff coming up over
the summer even though we're not going
to have any brand new shows now
um the whole point of this show this
week is the instant holographic portrait
printing system from Sony I had the
opportunity to go into New York City
this week and visit with Akira shirakura
who is in the United States right now at
the Sony building at 56th and Madison
Avenue in downtown Manhattan or Midtown
Manhattan actually
and if you have an opportunity to stop
by there they're open every day of the
week except for Monday and I think
Sunday's hours are actually noon to four
but you can have your own holographic
portrait done for five dollars it's a
small holographic portrait it's about
the size of a postage stamp I had one
done I took my daughter in and my
daughter had one done and it comes out
let me see if I can grab this here of
course this isn't allowing me to pick it
up
my daughter had one uh done as well they
put it on a little card I'm holding it
up to the camera now you probably won't
be able to see the image because the
image is rather small and see if I can
get it a little bit closer up there but
that's the card that it comes on
and let me just read the first
paragraph of the abstract here it says
the system consists of a capturing
camera a high-speed image processing
device and a desktop one-step
holographic stereogram printer
it takes less than three minutes to
obtain a horizontal Parallax 3D image
78 millimeter by 59 millimeter on Dupont
photopolymer film
and that also includes includes
capturing and the image processing time
so from the time you sit down and have
that camera it's actually a camera on a
rail that passes by you it takes seven
seconds
and I believe
295 individual pictures are processed in
that time but it only takes three
minutes for that hologram to be created
entirely automatically
now since the holographic stereogram
printer is designed for easy operation
under non-laboratory conditions an
anti-vibration table or a dark room is
not necessary and folks let me tell you
this camera is absolutely incredible the
the technology that's built into this
and they did a wonderful job and if you
look on the whole talk page you will see
a link going to the Sony page that I put
up which will contain a few diagrams
from this abstract that I have along
with a few photographs that I was able
to take of the unit itself during my
trip to New York and you'll be able to
get some information on how this works
and how wonderful it is to have
something like this isn't it incredible
now if you're an amateur Hobbies now
this is a prototype unit they're Sony at
this point in time is not making any
plans to make an announcement that this
unit's going to be available for
purchase or anything like that it's
completely a prototype unit
and if you are an amateur or hobbyist
holographer and you would like to do
your own holographic portraits there's
also a link on the whole talk page and
I'll have it on the Sony page as well
where I'm putting my manual together
right now and it's just about finished
I'm going to have it finished for June
where you can learn how to do your own
holographic portraits using your 35
millimeter camera and either your helium
neon laser or your laser diode whichever
one you choose and they're very nice
holographic portraits and it's portraits
is a wonderful thing for holography I
mean you can see Holograms of all these
different objects and all the different
things that you see in a hologram shop
but when you start to make hologram
portraits you are really personalizing
holography it becomes very meaningful to
someone when you do a holographic
portrait you could do a holographic
portrait of someone's grandparents so
that they could have a 3D hologram of
their grandparents how about the newborn
in the family or with this process it
doesn't necessarily have to be a person
you can take your 35 millimeter camera
outdoors
and do something inside of a museum or
maybe out in a park or something like
that and bring that film back in
and turn it into a three-dimensional
hologram it doesn't necessarily have to
be a portrait of a person so I'm going
to have this manual finish by June it's
it's quite a bit of work putting this
together it's a very simple process but
it has to be done accurately so I want
to make sure everything's right with it
and also I would suggest you check that
out as well when you're also checking
out the Sony page as well
so that about wraps it up but I want to
make this show too long because this is
not only audio but it's video and I have
no idea how big this file is going to be
but I imagine it's going to be pretty
huge so if you had an opportunity to
watch it would you do me a favor would
you send me an email and let me know
that you watched the show it would mean
a lot to me to see how many people have
chosen to either listen to the show or
have chosen to watch it and that
feedback that you've sent to me is very
valuable because it will let me know
just what the listeners and viewers want
with holography and information
presented to them so folks I want to
thank you very very much for tuning into
this show the last season it's the end
of its second season now the season
coming up in
1999-2000 season will be the third
season of holotalk and I've got a lot of
interesting ideas I want to work out and
a lot of interesting shows we will still
have a few things on the website over
the summer get yourself back on the
email list but I'm going to thank thank
you very much for tuning in and making
me feel welcome to come into your homes
your offices and your schools with laser
and holography information each week and
it's certainly been an honor to do this
and and God willing I'm looking forward
to coming back in the fall and starting
it all over again and always always
always making that making it better than
it was the last time so thank you very
much have a very safe and happy summer
and God willing I will see you in the
fall when whole Talk starts up on its
third season this is Frankie Freitas
signing off for the summer of 1999.
would you like to make your own
one-of-a-kind hologram and learn how you
can start making holograms on your own
at the same time you can do this and
much more by attending one of Frankie's
greatest holography workshops from
beginner to Advanced Frank's got a
workshop that's just right for you from
single afternoon evening or weekend
introductory workshops to Wednesday
evening five-week complete courses and
don't forget his newest Workshop laser
pointer holography located just off the
Northeast Extension of the Pennsylvania
Turnpike and Interstate 78 the studio is
a quick non-stop drive from the New York
Philadelphia and Baltimore Washington DC
areas for more information call the
Studio's toll-free hotline at
1-800-458-3525 and begin your own
Journey with holography today that's
1-800-458-3525 for more information on
attending Frankie Freda telegraphy
Workshop today
okay